啲 food。
on chapter one only.
行政長官質詢時間結束。
我有榮譽將我們的報告號碼71呈上今日。
Thank you, Mr President. On behalf of the Public Accounts Committee,
of the response rates and the long time taken to complete the field work.
委員會的報告表今天， covers our conclusions and recommendations.
Out of the ten chapters covered by the director of audits report number seventy-one.
In view of the number of issues raised in the other chapter, the committee has yet to defer a full report on it.
現在舉行立法會例行會議，發言石禮謙議員就政府帳目委員會第七十一號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議員。
委員會已決定聚焦於兩章節，relating to the work of the Centre for Food Safety, CFS。
The important keep-keeping task of keeping food safety in Hong Kong falls on CFS under the Food and Environmental Hygiene Department.
The Centre for Food Safety would conduct population-based food consumption surveys, for the purpose of collecting data on the types and amounts of food that people consume.
聽證會檢討章節一，關於CFS的管理，食物安全，和章節二，關於其進口控制。我哋將要檢討呢兩章節嘅細節。
我 now report the conclusions and recommendations on the chapter on the management of food safety by CFS. The committee stresses that the public health and safety food sold in Hong Kong must be safe and fit for consumption.
For the first survey conducted in March 2004, the committee expresses grave dismay and finds it unacceptable that the 42 months delay in this survey, while the progress of the survey was unsatisfactory in terms.
for instance。
和data analysis work.
and terminating the whole contract.
作為證實，由這慢進步，反映在監察長報告。
There were cases of non-compliance with sampling requirements in the food surveillance programme.
of the progress of the survey currently still underway and the performance of the contractor.
for the second population-based food consumption survey, which started in May 2017.
Furthermore, CFS has not effectively monitored the compliance of its staff with the available guidelines.
There was no provision in the contract to address such unsatisfactory performance, apart from withholding payment.
The rights and interests of government was not sufficiently protected under the foot for centres for foot for safety contract management.
noting that the contractor has made improvement with closer monitoring by the CFS, the committee urges the CFS to continue its close monitoring.
The committee again expresses grave dismay and finds it again unacceptable that the food for centre safety have not learnt a good lesson from the first survey.
more than 10% of the turnaround time of testing results in 2017 were more than 60 days, with the longest one being 230 days.
CFS have not provided sufficient guidelines for its staff on some major procedures, including the sampling, the workflow as well as the timing on announcing the food testing results.
The committee expresses serious concern and finds it again unacceptable that as that as a large number of some 66,000 food samples were taken annually for food testing.
控制通訊系統。
The committee notes that the.
capacity for food testing。
are sufficient to ensure that they could deal with the increasing workload.
和 urgent food incidents which required immediate attention and action.
for the other chapter on radio, television, Hong Kong provision of programme.
subsequent enhancement work would be included in the project scope in its paper to the finance committee.
pending the outcome of this review, the committee would further consider the need to take any further actions.
CFS is also urged to review whether its establishment, manpower and the available laboratory.
We would like to take this opportunity to express our appreciation to those bureau and department in providing detailed replies to our questions.
suggest the use of information technology to record relevant information and generate management reports for better monitoring of staff compliance with guidelines.
In reply to the committee, the Hong Kong Police Force have explained its reason for charging the expenditure of subsequent extension and enhancement work of the system to the system project budget over a period of some 10 years after the system rollout.
Radio, Television, Hong Kong and the Education Bureau are undertaking reviews on issues covered in this chapter, such as the nature and procedures of acquisition of television and radio programme, and the cost effectiveness of school education television.
Now I turn to the other chapters, Mr. President. The committee have also studied the other eight chapters by asking the relevant bureau and department to provide written replies to members' question on how they address the inadequacies raised in the director of audits' report.
The committee urges the CFS to review frequently the workflow of food surveillance, as well as the handling of food incidents and complaints, in order to revise, update existing guidelines and supplement new guidelines where necessary. The committee also sug
for the chapter on procurement of the operation equipment by the Hong Kong Police Force, the committee notes that there was an unspent balance of four hundred and four million dollars after the completion of two main contracts for the implementation of the third generation command and.
多謝主席。
主席。
for his unfailing support to the committee.
質詢第一項質詢，何俊賢議員。
such as public hearing， etc. on the chapter.
我感激，也感謝所有出席聽證會的證人。謝謝。
我感謝和期待繼續支持委員會的秘書處，委員會。
在Closing，我特別想表達我們對David Sun，退休從事審計主任的感謝。
Mr. John Chee, the incumbent director of audit, I would like to record my appreciation of the contribution made by members of the committee and the secretariat.
The committee considered this arrangement unsatisfactory, as the approval of the electoral finance committee of the system was not a blanket approval, and the police force should have included sufficient information, such as whether a phased implementation was adopted or.